const myCardsTitle = [
  {
    levelNumber: "4.7",
    title: "Modal verbs - mustn't, don't have to",
  },
];

const myCards = [
  {
    front: "Muszę skorzystać z telefonu.",
    back: "I have to use my phone./ I must use my phone.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie muszę używać telefonu. Mam laptopa.",
    back: "I don't have to use my phone. I have a laptop.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno mi używać telefonu podczas jazdy.",
    back: "I mustn't use my phone while driving."
  },
  {
    front: "Musisz coś zjeść.",
    back: "You have to eat something./ You must eat something.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie musisz jeść tej zupy, jeśli jej nie lubisz.",
    back: "You don't have to eat this soup if you don't like it.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno nic jeść przed operacją.",
    back: "You mustn't eat anything before the surgery.",
  },
  {
    front: "On musi napić się wody.",
    back: "He has to drink some water./ He must drink some water.",
  },
  {
    front: "On nie musi pić wody. Zostało trochę soku.",
    back: "He doesn't have to drink water. There is some juice left.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno mu pić alkoholu. On ma dopiero 15 lat!",
    back: "He mustn't drink alcohol. He's only 15!",
  },
  {
    front: "Ona musi bardzo ciężko trenować.",
    back: "She has to train very hard./ She must train very hard.",
  },
  {
    front: "Ona nie musi ciężko trenować. Jest w świetnej formie.",
    back: "She doesn't have to train hard. She's in a great shape.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno jej tak ciężko trenować. Jest w ósmym miesiącu ciąży!",
    back: "She mustn't train so hard. She's eight months pregnant!",
  },
  {
    front: "To musi być coś specjalnego.",
    back: "It has to be someting special.",
  },
  {
    front: "To nie musi być drogie.",
    back: "It doesn't have to be expensive.",
  },
  {
    front: "To nie może być drogie.",
    back: "It musn't be very expensive.",
  },
  {
    front: "W pracy musimy nosić uniformy.",
    back: "We have to wear uniforms at work./ We must wear uniforms at work.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie musimy nosić uniformów. Pracujemy z domu.",
    back: "We don't have to wear uniforms. We work from home.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno nam nosić czarnych uniformów. Muszą być białe.",
    back: "We musn't wear black uniforms. They must be white.",
  },
  {
    front: "Musicie nas odwiedzić.",
    back: "You have to visit us./ You must visit us.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie musicie nas odwiedzać. My was odwiedzimy.",
    back: "You don't have to visit us. We will visit you.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno wam go odwiedzać. Jest chory.",
    back: "You mustn't visit him. He's sick.",
  },
  {
    front: "Muszą odpowiedzieć na kilka pytań.",
    back: "They have to answer some questions.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie muszą odpowiadać na żadne pytania. Mogą milczeć.",
    back: "They don't have to answer any question. They can remain silent. ",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno im odpowiadać na żadne pytania bez adwokata.",
    back: "They mustn't answer any questions without their lawyer.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie musisz czytać tej książki.",
    back: "You don't have to read this book.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno ci czytać tej książki. To jest zabronione.",
    back: "You mustn't read this book. It's forbidden.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie musisz z nim rozmawiać.",
    back: "You don't have to talk to him.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno ci z nim rozmawiać.",
    back: "You mustn't talk to him.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie musimy oglądać tego nudnego filmu.",
    back: "We don't have to watch this boring movie.",
  },
  {
    front: "Nie wolno nam oglądać tego filmu. Jesteśmy za młodzi!",
    back: "We musn't watch this movie. We are too young!",
  },
];
export { myCardsTitle, myCards };
